A sound soul dwells within a sound mind and a sound body.
After sitting inside the magnetic field for 800 years, Avon's greatest tool, brew, has ceased to function.
And so, here we are. There is no more time to fool around.
Fortunately, the DWMA knows only that we have brew, not that it's no longer operational.
Before they can recover from their latest failure, we should move on to the next step of our plan.
Wouldn't you agree, Mosquito?
Yes, Lady Arachne, I agree completely.
How is our research on the moral manipulation machine progressing? Are we on schedule?
It's nearly complete. We're entering the final stages of research as we speak.
Faster than expected.
If we continue at this rate, it should be ready very soon.
Yes.
Ha! What do we need with some stupid machine?
Why not just leave the Academy agents to me? I'll destroy them all.
Naturally, since you did such a good job of destroying them during the battle on Lost Island.
I pulled back my forces, assuming you could handle your part of the mission. Was I wrong?
You shouldn't presume to comment on my job performance. It could be hazardous to your health.
What are you saying, old geezer?
Shall I spell it out for you? Watch your mouth, or I'll beat you to a bloody pulp.
I'd like to see that. Come on, try me.
Enough squabbling, you two.
Now, Mosquito, continue with your report.
Yes. We've begun installing stations at various points around the world.
Construction continues swiftly and efficiently. Everything is proceeding as planned.
Good. Now for the next step.
My darling children, go forth. Complete the task your mother has given you.
At last, arachnophobia finally begins its rightful ascendancy.
I'm falling down to my shadow.
To begin with.
Don't ski.
It's a scary dream, but it's a terrible dream
For you, it's a terrible dream
I'm wearing a black paper
If you gave it to me
When you're lost, you're young
Forever with your soul
You're young, you're young
You're young
And out of nowhere, we were besieged by hundreds of arachnophobia's most elite forces!
In the classroom, I may seem quiet
But in battle, all of that changes
In the end, all we managed to do was beat up on some old man and send him running back to arachnophobia
We don't even have brew to show for it
Nothing can change our failure
What happened?
Impossible! That technique's too advanced!
What he said when I used it
And that strange blast of light
Where did a move like that come from and how did I use it?
Is it connected to Sol's plane?
All we did was survive a small skirmish against one of the enemy
We gained absolutely nothing
Maybe I should talk to Lord Death about it
Everybody looks pretty depressed, huh?
It's not surprising
We risked a lot going to that island for a big fight
And arachnophobia still ended up with brew anyway
I know, but what's so depressing about that?
Why don't you sit quietly and think about it for a minute
Okay, sis, I'll try
By the way, what's up with Kid? I haven't seen him in a while
He said he was going to the bathroom, but now that you mention it, he has been gone a long time
What do you think he's gotten himself into now?
The detective's first case
Kid exposes the DWMA's secret?
What does the Academy know?
What does my father have planned?
What's he hiding?
He's been gathering every magic tool Abon created
He sent out the Academy troops to prevent brew from falling into the wrong hands
But he's not telling us everything
What are his true intentions?
What information has he been holding back?
I know there's more to this than there seems
Who is this great wizard Abon?
What does he have to do with my father?
I asked him about it and as expected he gave a half answer and then changed the subject
If he won't tell me, I'll find out for myself
Anyway, like I was saying, something's been bothering Kid lately. He seems a bit suspicious of your recent actions.
Hmm.
He's been poking around for information on his own. What should we do?
Poking around for information on his own. What should we do?
Poking around for information?
For information.
Hmm.
Anyway, like I was saying,
something's been bothering Kid lately.
He seems a bit suspicious of your recent actions.
He's been poking around for information on his own.
What should we do?
Poking around for information?
For information, that's right.
Hmm.
On his own?
Yes, on his own.
So, what should we do?
That's what I asked.
It's a difficult question.
None of us like going into this blind.
Eh?
Kid's not the only one.
I want to know what's going on, too.
Why are you collecting all of Abon's tools?
Why haven't you explained yourself to us?
What's your plan?
You want to know my plan?
Yes, of course I do.
You want me to explain?
I want you to explain.
That's what I just said.
Too bad.
I'm not going to tell you.
How old are you, 11?
Sid, Lord Death.
Good morning.
Yo, Meister Maka.
Great to see you.
How's it hanging?
Um, Lord Death,
there's something I wanted to ask you about.
Is now a good time?
Of course.
Ask away.
What do you want to know?
I'll tell you anything.
Hey now, can I get some equality here?
A genie hunter technique?
Yes.
The old man mosquito seems surprised to see me using it.
I was trying to do witch hunter,
and then this other technique came out instead.
I don't understand.
Are the two related?
Oh, our little Meister Maka has learned how to use the genie hunter, has she?
Amazing.
Oh, it's not that big a deal.
They grow up so quickly.
You're becoming more like your mother every day.
Huh?
This new genie hunter technique of yours.
I've only ever seen one Meister do it before you,
and that was your mother, my dear.
Are you serious?
My mother?
Yep.
As the name genie hunter suggests,
it's a special move that works against particularly evil forces.
Only a superior Meister like your mother could control it.
She truly was a talented young woman, you know.
Who would have thought you'd follow in her steps so quickly?
This is an amazing achievement.
Congratulations.
If you continue improving at this rate,
who knows, you may even be able to defeat the Kishen.
I don't know about that.
I know this game.
When I was alive, I too was very adept at flattery.
But this isn't over yet.
We still have a long way to go before victory is ours.
I expect you to keep working hard.
Right.
See ya!
Following in my mother's footsteps.
Never thought Maka's abilities would awaken so soon.
This is incredible.
It's good news, indeed.
With a little more progress,
the power to annihilate the Kishen may very well be in her hands.
Anyway, Sid, back to business.
Sir?
The package we spoke of.
Has it been delivered yet?
What do you mean?
You remember?
The package.
I believe I asked you to locate a certain gentleman in Oceania and bring him here.
Oh, I get it now.
The package, of course.
It should be delivered very soon, sir.
Indeed.
That's good to hear.
Heedless of my own safety,
I plunged into the magnetic field.
And then there was a great explosion!
The terror of it would have made a lesser man weep.
Give me a break.
Like, that's really how it happened.
Sit down and shut your big, lying mouth!
Okay.
Was the battle on Lost Island really as difficult as Ox says it was?
Yes.
Skirmishes with arachnophobia broke out all over the island.
He should shut up.
I don't know what he thinks we have to be so proud of.
We failed, remember?
Arachnophobia has brew now.
We lost the fight that mattered.
Yeah, that's true, but it could have been worse.
Your piano playing was awesome, Sol.
Without that, who knows what would have happened to us.
Yep.
Look at it that way.
Everybody returned home safe and sound.
We managed to get away without anyone being hurt.
Surely that's more important.
Did we, though?
What about the professor?
I wonder how he's doing.
Do you mean Professor Stein?
Mm-hmm.
He collapsed suddenly while we were on the island.
It was frightening.
Oh.
He's probably at home recovering today.
I hope it's nothing serious.
What's happening to him?
Is it my fault?
If I hadn't planted that snake in Miss Marie's coffee,
would Professor Stein be okay still?
You look sick, Krona.
Is something wrong?
No, I'm fine.
It's nothing to worry about, really.
Nothing, nothing at all.
He's kind of an odd duck, isn't he?
Hey, Krona.
You should eat.
You're looking pale.
Uh, yeah.
What should I do?
Okay, what's going on?
Just come with me.
Why should I?
Where are we going?
Over there.
That's very specific.
Thanks.
Hurry up.
We need to practice it again before we forget how it works.
What are you talking about?
That new technique.
Lord Death thinks we might be able to use it to beat the Kishin.
Huh?
So we need extra practice.
It's not there.
Don't you get it?
There.
That's better now.
Excuse me, Professor Stein.
Are you feeling okay?
Feeling okay?
Of course.
Why wouldn't I be?
Although I suppose saying that doesn't guarantee everyone will believe me, does it?
I want to ask you something.
What exactly does Brew do?
Can you tell me?
You already know that Brew is one of Ebon's magic tools.
He was a prominent inventor and created many impressive devices in his time, but Brew is the most powerful of them all.
True to its name, the tool's magic promises all the strength and danger of a brewing thunderstorm.
The results of its use can vary greatly depending on the person who wields it.
Be more specific.
I want to know what the tool actually does.
Is it there?
Tell me this, then.
What does my father plan to do with Brew?
What will the results be if he's the one who uses it?
If you aren't sure, you can speculate.
As a professor, you should have a guess.
What will you do with the information?
I can see that you're impatient for answers, but nothing I tell you will be of any use in the long run.
I can promise you that much.
Besides which, how could you fully accept whatever I might say while I'm in this condition?
Would that be a good idea?
Well, I don't know.
I'm sure you're willing to listen to my answers.
That's the easy part.
But then what comes after that?
What do you intend to do after you know all that I have to tell?
Extra practices aren't cool at all.
That kind of thing is only good for teachers, pets, and straight-A students.
Well, I am a straight-A student.
Now, would you transform into a scythe?
Come on, Sol!
All right, all right.
Quit whining.
I'm doing it.
You ready?
Just waiting on you.
Let's go, Sol Resonance!
Genie Hunter!
Huh?
That isn't right.
This is Witch Hunter.
Why isn't it becoming Genie Hunter?
Why didn't it work this time?
Are you being lazy because you don't feel like practicing?
Come off it, Maka.
If I was being lazy, how could we have done Witch Hunter?
Yeah, you have a point there.
But why then?
Maybe because we're not even sure how we did it the first time.
What's with the face?
A new technique always takes a little while.
Isn't that why we're practicing?
Yes.
Let's try it again.
Bring it on!
What is Arachne up to now?
She sent those little spiders of hers out everywhere.
They're all across the world.
She's up to something.
I'm sure of it.
Whatever her plan is, it's starting to move forward.
Thank you for reporting in.
If there's any further news, I'd appreciate being kept informed of the situation.
I'll let you know.
Things are moving along exactly as I'd hoped.
What else?
Have you noticed any changes?
Uh, no.
I haven't seen anything out of the ordinary.
Well, have you at least found out the location of the secret vault?
Oh, yeah, that.
Not yet.
You should at least have something by now.
Do you want to stay with your pals at the Academy or not?
It's just...
Ribbit?
This whole business with the snake we planted inside Miss Marie.
The snake?
What about it?
Something's happening.
I think it's hurting Professor Stein.
Oh, did I forget to tell you?
It's working well.
You did a very good job with that.
We've got brew now, and it's all thanks to that little snake.
We've knocked one of the Academy's best Meisters out of the game,
and we didn't even have to get involved in the battle.
It's my fault.
I did this.
You're shivering.
What's wrong?
No, I'm fine.
Good.
Now you should get going.
Don't you have more work to see to?
Medusa's counting on you, Crona.
You wouldn't want to let her down.
That's enough.
I don't think we need to practice any more today.
Come on.
Let's go back.
Get up.
I don't understand.
Why can't we do it?
Who knows?
We did it before.
Why not now?
We know it exists now.
That's what matters.
We did it once.
It's bound to happen again sooner or later.
Just not quite yet.
I'm so hungry I could eat a horse.
Which reminds me, it's your turn to cook dinner tonight.
I forgot to shop.
We're out of food.
Why, you!
Sorry.
Looks like PB&J tonight.
You gotta be kidding me!
Right now, it doesn't matter what I want.
I can't ignore something just because I don't want to see it.
You can't turn a blind eye, not even for your own father?
I can't make exceptions.
Anyone who strays from the right path must be stopped.
But who decides which path is the right one?
And how do you recognize when someone has strayed from it?
It's simple.
The truth is easy to see when you know right from wrong.
Oh, is it really?
You're quite naive, aren't you?
About what?
Let me ask you this.
Where does this knowledge of yours come from?
This ability to know right and wrong?
There is no inherent good or evil in the world.
Those labels are just artificial constructs.
Right and wrong are determined by the people who hold positions of authority.
That's the way it's always been.
So how then can anyone know this truth you speak of?
Don't you see?
The reality is that truth long ago became nothing more than a shadow of itself.
It's a mere echo of the past now.
You're wrong.
Idealistic boy.
The world is one big moral gray area.
It just makes you feel safer to believe that it can be carefully categorized into good and bad.
That's not actually how it works.
You're wrong!
Why are you so determined about this, kid?
Why are you still refusing to answer any of my questions?
What information are you so desperate to keep hidden?
Hmm.
Oh, hi, kid.
What's going on here?
Say you're right.
Doesn't that still make the Academy the authority that determines what right and wrong are?
Huh.
Is that truly how you think it works?
On that point, I fear I must once again disagree with you completely.
Things at the Academy aren't always as black and white as you'd like to believe they are.
He's finally here.
Joe Butataki.
Technology consultant from the Oceaniaic Division of the DWMA.
Death City.
I made it.
My new workplace.
Well, let's get started.
We'll be right back.
Kid, you idiot. Have you found anything yet?
Soul sounds a little discontent.
Me? What are you talking about?
Discontent and angry.
Oh, please.
Discontent, angry, and impatient.
Hey, I'm not... never mind.
And in denial, too.
On the next episode of Soul Eater,
Ashura's temptation,
the big man's uncontrollable irritation,
Soul is desperate for attention.
Just stick to watch it or I'll take your soul.
That's my line.